

# Ali Asghar Momeni Vesalian

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - JAVA

#### **PROFILE**

Gender: Male

**Nationality**: Iranian **Birth Date**: 6/30/1985

Software engineer with a strong background in design and development on Java platform. Keen learner and problem solver with a passion for algorithms, architecture, high throughput systems and Big Data. Highly experienced in developing financial and banking systems.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Master of Science** from Tehran Markazi Azad University in Software Engineering from September 2015 to Present.

**Bachelor of Science** from Qazvin Azad University in Software Engineering from September 2003 to September 2008.

#### **LANGUAGES**

English

Persian

#### **CONTACT**

Email: momeni.vesalian@gmail.com

Mobile: +98 912 020 6542

LinkedIn: Momeni Vesalian's profile Address: Flat 1, No. 5, Layeqi Alley, Qasr-od-Dasht St., Azarbayejan St.,

Tehran, Iran

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Sava Arman Kish (Bitex)

### Senior Java Developer

June 2018 - Present

- Work as a chief architect of an exchange project
- Design architecture model and implement architectural APIs
- Design and implement matching engine

#### Navaco (Maskan Bank)

#### Senior Java Developer

Mar 2017 - June 2018

- Worded as a member of CORE Banking architecture team
- Designed architecture model and implemented some architectural APIs
- Designed and implemented lending overnight calculation

#### Caspian (Parsian Bank)

#### Senior Java Developer and Designer

Sep 2014 - Mar 2017

- Worked as a member of Lending team
- Designed and implemented conversion's architecture model
- Wrote 30000+ lines of Java and PL-SQL code

#### Rayan Eghtesad Novin (Eghtesad Novin Bank)

#### **Software Designer**

May 2013 - Sep 2014

- Worked as a member of Lending team
- Designed repayment and settlement functionalities

## Caspian (Parsian Bank)

#### Java Developer and Designer

Sep 2009 - May 2013

- Worked as a member of Lending team
- Designed and implemented repayment, settlement, installment table calculation
- Wrote 150000+ lines of Java code

#### IT and Communication Organization of Tehran Municipality

#### Java Developer

Oct 2008 - Sep 2009

- Worked as a member of Media Observatory team
- Implemented several functionalities



# Ali Asghar Momeni Vesalian

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - JAVA

# PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Java 8	Spring
Design Patterns	Spring Boot
SOA	Spring MVC
Microservices	Spring Batch
Event Driven Architecture	Spring Security
Software Architecture Patterns	Spring Data / JPA
Big Data Architecture	Hibernate / EclipseLink / iBatis
Big Data Concepts	Vert.x
Live Migration	Redis
Concurrent Programming	Oracle PL/SQL Development
Reactive Programming	Gradle / Maven
RESTful Web Services	Git / Subversion
Docker and Docker Compose	Test Driven Development
CI / CD	JUnit / Power Mock / JMockit
Jenkins	Hadoop / Spark / Storm
Swagger	UML / Agile and RUP Methodologies
Eureka / Ribbon / Hystrix Netflix	CORE Banking Systems
OSGi / Blueprint	Lending System Developer
Apache Karaf	Crypto Currency Exchanges
JAAS	Exchange Developer
<u>I</u> ATEX	